So here we are on Hugging Face's main landing page at Hugging Face Core.
여기는 H징 페이스코어의 주 랜딩 페이지인데요
A URL you know.
URL 같은 거요
Well, since we produced the company brochure for Hugging Face a couple of times.
얼굴 안기기 팸플릿을 몇 번 제작한 후부터요
And, uh, this is this is what you'll see.
이게 여러분이 보시게 될 거예요
If you're not logged in, you don't have an account.
로그인 안 하면 계정이 없어요
You'll see a screen like this.
이런 화면이 보일 거예요
And the first thing you need to do is go to sign up.
가장 먼저 할 일은 등록하는 거예요
If you don't already have a hugging face account, it is free to join email address and a password and
포옹 얼굴 계정이 아직 없다면 이메일 주소와 비밀번호를 무료로 등록하면
then you will be in.
가입할 수 있어요
And once you're in, you'll get to see something like this.
get it에 들어가면 이런 걸 보게 돼요
Uh, the main navigation of Hugging Face is up here, and you can see the first three parts of the main
페이스 포옹의 주 내비게이션은 이 위에 있어요 내비게이션의 첫 세 부분은 모델,
navigation are models, datasets and spaces.
데이터셋, 스페이스예요
And that is what we're going to look at right now.
지금 그걸 살펴볼 거예요
So the first tab models, this is where in the hugging face platform or the hub as it's known, you
첫 번째 탭 모델은 포옹형 플랫폼 혹은 허브라고 불리는 곳에서 사용
can see all of the models that are available to you.
가능한 모든 모델을 볼 수 있어요
I said before that it's more than 800,000 is in fact more than 900,000.
800,000개 이상이라고 했는데 사실은 900,000개 이상이죠
Look at that.
보세요
And this is sorted, I think, by default by trending, which is some combination of recency and popularity.
이건 정렬된 것 같아요 기본 트렌딩으로요 재조정과 인기를 합친 거죠
You can also turn that into by how popular it is, how many times it's been downloaded and how recently
얼마나 유명한지도 바꿀 수 있어요 얼마나 많이 다운로드되었는지 얼마나 최근에 생성되거나
it was created or updated.
업데이트되었는지도요
As you can see here, the name of each of these models is typically the name of the organization and
보시다시피 각각의 모델의 이름은 전형적으로 조직의 이름이고 다음은
then the name of the model.
모델 이름이죠
Flux is one of the latest and most exciting text to image models, and I do believe we'll be playing
플럭스는 가장 최신의 이미지 모델 텍스트 중 하나입니다 언젠가 그걸 갖고 놀 거라고
with that at some point.
믿어요
Quanta, the powerhouse model from Alibaba Cloud that I've mentioned a few times now.
퀀타는 제가 몇 번 언급했던 알리바바 클라우드의 강력한 모델이죠
And you can see typically you have the number of parameters often in the description of a lamb.
보통 양을 묘사할 때 매개 변수의 수를 볼 수 있어요
And then instruct at the end tells us that this has been fine tuned to be most applicable during a sort
그리고 마지막에 지시 사항은 채팅이나 입력 상호 작용을 지시할 때 가장
of chat and instruct kind of interaction with the input.
잘 적용되도록 조율되었다는 것을 알려줘요
And we can see lots of other models here.
다른 모델도 많이 있어요
There's of course a filter up here.
물론 필터가 있죠
So we can filter on something like llama to look at the llama model, which was Meta's model, which
llama 같은 것을 필터링해 llama 모델을 볼 수 있어요 메타 모델이죠 아주
is so very well known, so very popular.
유명하고 인기 있는 거예요
Here it is.
여기 있네요
These are all various um, times that meta or llama will have been mentioned at some point in these
이 모든 게 다양한 시기예요 메타나 라마가 이 묘사에 나오는 어느 시점에서 언급되겠죠
descriptions.
하지만 우리가 정말 원하는 건 여기 메타 라마 3이에요 180억 버전 모델이죠
And that's the same one fine tuned for the instruct use case.
교육 사용 사례에 잘 맞춰진 것과 같은 거죠
The this kind of uh um chat use case.
이런 종류의 채팅 사용 사례요
So let's go in here.
이쪽으로 오세요
If you go into llama 3.18 billion, you see a ton of information about it.
라마 3에 가시면요 180억 개에 관한 정보가 엄청나게 많아요
You see that it's been downloaded a large number of times.
여러 번 다운로드된 게 보이시죠
Uh, recently we'll be downloading it ourselves, I think, on many occasions over the coming weeks.
최근에는 직접 다운로드도 할 거예요 앞으로 몇 주간 자주 그럴 거예요
Uh, you get some information about the model architecture, uh, the languages, the family, the how
모델 아키텍처에 대한 정보도 얻을 수 있고 언어, 가족, 사용 의도에 대한 정보도
it's intended to be used, and then some code examples down at the end.
얻을 수 있습니다. 그리고 코드 예제도 볼 수 있어요.
Uh, so this is all useful stuff to read about.
전부 다 유용한 책이에요
Also information about how it was trained.
어떻게 훈련했는지도 알려줘요
Um, and lots of other things worth reading about.
그 외에도 읽을 만한 게 많아요
There's also this tab here, Files and Versions, which opens up something that looks a bit like a git
파일과 버전이라는 탭도 있어요 Git 저장소처럼 보이는 뭔가를 여는
repository.
탭이죠
And it's funny you should think that because it actually is a git repository.
그렇게 생각하다니 재미있네요 사실 그건 Git 저장소거든요
A lot of what you can think of the hugging face hub as is a sort of interface on top of a series of
포옹하는 얼굴 허브는 git 리포스 시리즈의 인터페이스로 생각할
git repos.
수 있어요
And often when you're downloading a model or downloading data, what you're really doing is doing a
모델이나 데이터를 다운로드할 때 실제로 하는 일은 일종의 Git get에서
sort of a pull from git get and getting these files locally.
끌어와 이 파일들을 로컬로 가져오는 거죠
So this is the the the the folder and file structure that sits behind the meta llama 3.18 billion.
이게 메타 llama 3 뒤에 있는 폴더와 파일 구조예요 180억 달러요
And there are various ways that you can use it.
다양한 방법으로 사용할 수 있어요
There's a button here.
여기 버튼이 있어요
Use this model that will give you more information if you go into it on what you need to do.
여러분이 해야 할 일에 대해 더 많은 정보를 주는 이 모델을 사용하세요
That gives you actual examples of code.
실제 코드 예제를 제공하죠
We'll be using this code later, so don't worry about it right now.
이 코드는 나중에 쓸 거니까 지금은 신경 쓰지 마세요
You don't need to to read this, but know that you can always go to use this model.
이걸 읽을 필요는 없지만 언제든 이 모델을 사용할 수 있다는 걸 알아두세요
Select Transformers, which means you want to use it using hugging face Transformers library, and then
얼굴 트랜스포머 라이브러리를 사용하려면 트랜스포머를 선택하세요 사용자
copy code examples directly from the user interface.
인터페이스에서 예제를 직접 복사하세요
As simple as that.
아주 간단해요
And there's other stuff here that we'll look at another day.
다른 건 나중에 살펴보죠
There's some tags of course, which also allows you to filter on different, uh, aspects of models
물론 태그도 있어요 모델의 다양한 측면을 아주 빠르고 쉽게 필터링할
very quickly and easily.
수 있게 해주죠
We'll be looking at lots of other models in time.
다른 모델도 많이 볼 거예요
We'll be looking at things like the Phi model from Microsoft and which I think I mentioned.
마이크로소프트의 파이 모델 같은 것을 살펴볼 것입니다 제가 언급했던 것 같네요
We'll be looking, of course, at quanta, and that you've actually already seen and plenty of others.
물론 퀀타도 살펴볼 겁니다 이미 많이 보셨을 거예요
Maybe I'll mention Google's Gemma that you'll see Gemma will come up when I do this.
구글의 제마를 언급할까 봐요 제가 이걸 할 때 제마가 나올 거예요
Um, it did come up and then it went away.
네, 떴다가 다시 사라졌어요
So let's do Google slash Gemma.
구글 또는 제마로 해보죠
There we go.
됐어요
Um, so this, for example, the 2 billion very small on device version of Gemma and it as before has
예를 들어 20억 개의 아주 작은 장치 버전의젬마와 이전처럼 설명이 있어요 코드
the description, the code examples, the files and versions and the ability to use this model just
예제, 파일과 버전 그리고 이렇게 클릭해서 이 모델을 사용할
by clicking there like so.
수 있는 기능도요
That's models.
모형이에요
Let's move on to data sets.
데이터 집합으로 넘어가죠
Data sets shows you the vast resource of data that's available on the Hugging Face hub.
데이터 집합은 페이스 허브에서 사용 가능한 방대한 데이터 리소스를 보여주죠
And again, you've got the ability to search.
검색 기능도 있고요
It's sorted by default on trending.
기본값으로 정렬되어 있어요.
And let me say later on, we're going to be doing some experiments using prices of products.
나중에 말씀드릴게요 제품 가격을 이용한 실험을 할 거예요
And one of the things we'd love to see is some sort of scrape of product data.
저희가 보고 싶은 건 긁힌 제품 데이터예요
And it turns out there is in fact, there are a bunch of repositories of data related to prices on Amazon.
알고 보니 아마존 가격과 관련된 데이터 저장소가 정말 많더라고요
Here is some of them.
여기 몇 개 있네요
You can have a look around the popularity of them and which ones are useful.
어떤 게 인기 있고 어떤 게 유용한지 살펴보세요
We are in fact going to be using this one here, which is very recent and which is very comprehensive
여기 있는 이걸 사용할 겁니다 아주 최근 것으로 포괄적이고
indeed and has tons of useful data.
유용한 데이터가 아주 많아요
So it's absolutely phenomenal resource.
정말 경이로운 자원이에요
So do take a look at this and you can you can also use things like data set viewers and other tools
이걸 보세요 데이터 세트 뷰어 같은 것도 사용할 수 있어요 데이터 세트와 함께
that come with the data sets.
오는 다른 도구도요
Part of the Huggingface hub spaces I mentioned is where Gradio radio apps and other kinds of apps can
H깅페이스 허브 공간의 일부는 Gadio 라디오 앱과 다른 종류의 앱이 실행되는 곳입니다 커뮤니티의
run to do things that people in the community want to show off to others, or just get to get people
사람들이 남들에게 자랑하고 싶어 하거나 사용하게 만드는 작업을 위해서요
And you can do the same with your hugging face apps or your radio apps.
포옹하는 얼굴 앱이나 라디오 앱도 똑같이 할 수 있어요
There's a lot of things to try out here.
여긴 시도해 볼 게 많아요
Uh, there's uh, there's sort of spaces of the week.
금주의 공간 같은 게 있어요
There's there's things that are trending, and then there's a few types of spaces that we will be looking
요즘 추세인 것들이 있어요 그리고 몇 가지 유형의 공간이 있는데
at a lot more in the next few or probably next week, mostly about leaderboards, comparing different
다음 몇 주나 다음 주에 더 자세히 살펴볼 겁니다 대부분 리더보드죠 다양한 LMS를 비교하는
LMS.
거요
Um, there's a plenty of fun spaces where you can try out different interesting LMS or generative AI
흥미로운 LMS나 재생 인공지능 애플리케이션을 시험해 볼 수 있는 재미있는 공간이
applications.
많아요
Um, one of the things I do tend to find is that sometimes because a lot of these are running for free
제가 발견하는 것 중 하나는 가끔 이런 거예요 많은 것들이 무료로 실행되고
on free boxes, it can be a bit flaky in that if it's a popular one, then it's overused and it's quite
있기 때문에 약간 비트가 있을 수 있어요 만약 인기가 있는 것이라면 과용이 되고 실행하기가
hard to get it to run because it will tell you that it's too busy right now.
꽤 어렵죠 지금 너무 바쁘다고 알려 주거든요
Um, but I think that comes with the territory of free software.
하지만 그건 프리 소프트웨어 영역에 따라오는 거라고 생각해요
When it does work, it is wonderful.
효과가 있으면 정말 좋죠
So, for example, I just tried out a couple that were in the top spaces.
예를 들어, 상단 스페이스에 있는 걸 몇 개 시도해봤어요
So this one here, the AI Comic Factory, you can give it a style, you can give it a title of your
인공지능 코믹 팩토리에는 스타일과 제목을 줄 수 있고 제작할 때 어떤
comic and give it some something about how you want it to think when it's producing it.
생각을 하길 바라는지 알려줄 수 있어요
And I did a super powered data scientist comic, and you get this very cross looking, presumably the
슈퍼 파워 데이터 사이언스 만화를 그렸는데 악당으로 추정되는 인물이 매우 화난 표정으로
villain, and then you get presumably the heroine saying data is power, but sometimes it needs a little
나오고 여주인공은 데이터가 힘이라고 하지만 가끔은 좀 더 밀어붙여야
push.
해요
And so it's great fun.
정말 재미있어요
This is an imagined created comic strip based on a topic that you choose, and I encourage you to come
여러분이 선택한 주제에 기반해 상상으로 그린 만화입니다 여러분도 와서 한번
in and give it a try.
해 보세요
It did take me 2 or 3 tries before I got this because it was too much in demand, but it's for me.
두세 번 시도한 끝에 겨우 이걸 얻었어요 워낙 인기가 많았거든요 하지만 제 취향이에요
It's on the first page of Most Popular right now, but if you find this or something like it, give
현재 가장 인기 있는 사이트 첫 페이지에 있지만 이런 걸 발견하시면 한번
it a try.
써 보세요
Another thing that I tried out that was available was this.
제가 시도했던 또 다른 방법은 이거였어요
This is pretty funny.
이거 정말 웃기네요
You can upload an image of yourself.
자신의 사진을 업로드 할 수 있어요
I chose the one with me in front of the plane from before, which I cannot fly.
아까 비행기 앞에서 탔던 비행기를 선택했어요 전 못 타지만요
But that hasn't stopped me from trying.
그래도 계속 노력했어요
And then you can pick a garment or upload a garment, and then it will show you wearing that garment.
옷을 고르거나 업로드 하면 그 옷을 입은 모습이 나와요
I mean, it's all right.
아니, 괜찮아요
It's not perfect.
완벽하지 않아요
I don't know what's happening.
무슨 일인지 모르겠어요
I'm sort of hunched up like this a bit, but it gives you the idea.
약간 구부정하긴 하지만 비트를 보면 알 수 있죠
It's interesting to see that some sort of strange artifact has happened with the plane behind me.
제 뒤에 있는 비행기와 기이한 물체가 충돌하다니 흥미롭네요
Uh, but, um, aside from that, it's fun.
하지만 그것만 빼면 재밌어요
It's free, it's easy to use, and it's a classic example of people having good ideas about fun things
무료에 사용도 쉽고 인공지능이나 LM으로 할 수 있는 재미있는 일을 사람들이
you can do with AI, with Llms, and have surfaced it for others to play with.
떠올리는 전형적인 예죠 다른 사람들이 갖고 놀 수 있게 드러난 거예요
You will find many examples of this on spaces.
스페이스에 이런 예가 많아요
Uh, so then the other thing I wanted to show you, is to show you what happens if you go to to the
여러분께 보여드리고 싶은 또 다른 건 아바타 메뉴에서 자신을 보면 어떻게 되는지
avatar menu and look at yourself.
보여드릴게요
So here is, um, the, uh, I'm just going to go straight here.
여기서 바로 시작할 거예요
Uh, I can see my own what I've done.
제가 한 일을 보면 알아요
I have one space, I've got a bunch of different models, some of which will be playing with ourselves,
한 스페이스가 있고 다양한 모델이 여러 개 있어요 일부는 우리 자신을 갖고 놀겠죠 데이터 세트도
and I've got a bunch of data sets, and they're all private.
여러 개 있는데 모두 개인이에요
You can make them private if you only want to have access to them, or public if you want the world
오직 보고 싶을 때만 볼 수 있는 개인용으로 만들 수도 있고 온 세상이 보길 원한다면 공개용으로
to see them.
만들 수도 있죠
Um, and I've got various data sets that we will be talking about many of these in the next few weeks,
다양한 데이터 모음이 있는데 앞으로 몇 주 동안 많이 얘기할 거예요
and I think you'll have fun with them.
재미있을 거예요
Uh, and this space that I've got, for example, I also will might refer to, um, just just as an
예를 들어 여기 이 공간은 이런 작업이 얼마나 쉬운지 보여주는
example of how easy it is to do this stuff.
예가 될 거예요
But in this case, this is public and this is a game that I built which allows you to have llms compete
하지만 이 경우엔 공용이고 제가 만든 게임으로 llm들이 서로 경쟁하며 배틀을
against each other to try to battle.
시도하게 할 수 있죠
It was inspired by the the battle, the leadership battle we had in the first week.
첫 주에 있었던 리더십 싸움에서 영감을 받았어요
And I beefed that up a bit to make something where different lambs can fight in a way, to try and outwit
거기에 비트를 더해서 양들이 서로 싸우면서 서로 이기려고 하고 돈을
each other and take money from each other, following some rules.
뺏으려고 해요 규칙을 따르면서요
And you can play a game and watch it run.
게임을 하면서 달리는 걸 볼 수 있죠
Maybe we'll do that when we talk about the differences between lambs next week, I'll see if we have
다음 주에 양들의 차이점을 얘기할 때 해 보죠 시간이 되는지 볼게요
time.
그렇지 않다면, 직접 와서 제가 어떻게 했는지 보세요. LLM
an example of how it's easy to take an LLM application with either a gradio front end.
응용 프로그램이 얼마나 쉬운지 예로 볼 수 있습니다. 그러디오 프런트 엔드를 이용하거나
In this case, this is called Streamlit, a different kind of user interface or others.
이 경우에 이것은 Streamlit이라고 합니다. 다른 종류의 사용자 인터페이스 같은 것이죠.
And then publish it to be available to everyone on huggingface spaces.
그리고 포옹의 공간에 있는 모든 사람이 볼 수 있게 출판하는 거죠
One more thing about this menu that's worth mentioning is that if you go to your profile and your,
이 메뉴에 대해 한 가지 더 언급할 것은 프로필로 가시면 죄송합니다,
uh, sorry, if you go to your settings, I mean, down here to settings, uh, down here is a section
설정으로 가시면, 이 아래 설정으로요 이 아래에는 액세스 토큰이라는 섹션이
called Access Tokens.
있어요
This is something you need to do if you haven't done it before.
한 번도 안 해 본 사람은 꼭 해 봐야 해요
You go to access tokens and then there's a simple button create new token.
액세스 토큰으로 가서 간단한 버튼으로 새 토큰을 생성하세요
You press that to give yourself a new token, a new API token, where you will ask for both read and
그걸 눌러 새 API 토큰을 주는 거죠 새 API 토큰이요 읽기와 쓰기 사용 권한을 둘 다 요청하는
write permissions.
거죠
That is a token that we'll be using in Jupyter in order to get access to the hub, and in order to both
Jupyter에서 사용할 토큰으로 허브에 접근하고 모델과 데이터를 다운로드
download and upload models and data.
및 업로드 하기 위해서죠
So that is a key part of setting up your hugging face account.
포옹 얼굴 계정 설정에서 중요한 부분이죠
And that concludes our very quick tour of all things hugging face.
얼굴 맞대기 시범은 이걸로 간단히 마칠게요
There's so much to explore.
탐험할 게 정말 많아요
The to do for you is now go in.
이제 안으로 들어가세요
If you haven't already, set up your account, set up your API key, it's all free.
아직 계정과 API 키를 설정하지 않으셨다면 모두 무료예요
And then go hunt up models for datasets and look around some of the spaces and try out some of the cool
데이터셋 모델을 찾고 공간을 둘러보면서 사람들이 커뮤니티에서 누구나 사용할 수
products that people have made available for all of the community to try.
있게 만든 멋진 제품을 시도해 보세요
Enjoy that.
맛있게 드세요